Dwayne (DJ) Toler

Software Engineer

dwaynetoler@gmail.com | 248-416-9553 | Detroit, Mi | Linkedin.com/in/dwayne-toler | [GitHub.com/djtoler]

SUMMARY

Highly motivated and dedicated software engineering. Graduate of Grand Circus of Detroit, Michigan with 6 months experience in software development and over 7 years experience in data driven problem solving. After 9 years in the automotive industry I am transitioning from a career of leading production teams to a back-end developer. Looking to use proven skills in JavaScript and Node.js, along with database manipulation skills, to help solve business problems daily.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Grand Circus JavaScript Bootcamp: Detroit, MI November, 2021 – February, 2022 Memory Game App, Pizza Ordering App

Google Data Analytics Certification Lean Six Sigma Black Belt Certification Project Management Associate Certification

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML / CSS
- TypeScript
- React
- Web APIs

- Node.JS
- TDD/Jest Testing MySQL
 - PostgreSQL
 - MongoDB
 - Postman/Insomnia
 - GitBash / GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Lead Coordinator

General Motors, Detroit, Mi

June 2012 - October 2021

- Led a team of up to 16 assembly operators in lean production improvement efforts using data-driven strategies & project management techniques.
- Analyzed real-time incoming data attributes to create and lead over 25 documented problem solving projects
- Led over 150 weekly team meetings & data presentations with senior-level management & production operators
- Increased throughput production on several job operations by up to 73% using data analytics techniques, lean six sigma strategies & leading problem solving projects

Franchise Operator

January 2011 – November 2012

Vanguard Cleaning Services, Bloomfield Hills, Mi

- Led a franchise operation that employed 2 people.
- Planned & deployed strategic cleaning services to businesses in the Metro-Detroit area.
- Tracked task completion time and devised efforts that decreased elapsed service time by up to 25% at select locations

Real Estate Transaction Coordinator

September 2008 – December 2011

WGA Realty, Royal Oak, Mi

- Used data collecting & reporting strategies to reduce homeowners mortgage debt by up to 60%
- Compiled data-focused reports used to negotiate home short sale discounts with top lending institutions on behalf of homeowners in the Metro-Detroit area.